<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Created using XmlSitemapGenerator.org - Free HTML, RSS and XML sitemap generator-->
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
    <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz</link>
    <description />
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</link>
      <description>Income tax, Company law and Business service provider in Bangladesh</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/feed.xml</guid>
      <title>feed.xml</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/feed.xml</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/legal-environment-of-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/legal-environment-of-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>Bangladesh is a common law based jurisdiction. Many of the basic laws of Bangladesh such as penal code, civil and criminal procedural codes, contract law and company law are influenced by English common laws. However family laws such as laws relating to marriage, dissolution of marriage and inheritance are based on religious scripts, and therefore differ between religious communities. The Bangladeshi legal system is based on a written constitution and the laws often take statutory forms which are enacted by the legislature and interpreted by the higher courts. Ordinarily executive authorities and statutory corporations cannot make any law, but can make by-laws to the extent authorized by the legislature. Such subordinate legislation is known as rules or regulations and is also enforceable by the court. Yet being a common law system, the statutes are short, and set out basic rights and responsibilities but are elaborated by the courts in their application and interpretation of those. In addition, certain customs and practices established over a period are also to some extent recognized as acceptable and are enforced by the courts.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/revenue-regime-of-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/revenue-regime-of-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>The current fiscal regime of Bangladesh consists of direct and indirect taxation. It is governed by the
National Board of Revenue (NBR). Revenue is also generated from non-NBR sectors and under the laws
and acts of related ministries. The NBR taxes include Customs Duty, Value Added Tax (VAT),
Supplementary Duty (SD), Personal Income Taxes (PIT) and Corporate Income Taxes (CIT).
Personal and Corporate Income Tax, the single largest source of direct tax, is governed by the Income
Tax Ordinance, 1984 (XXXVI of 1984). The income tax laws consist of the following statutes (apart from
the main statute):

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/major-policy-reforms-and-their-impact/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/major-policy-reforms-and-their-impact/</link>
      <description>There have been some policy discussions about the tax law in Bangladesh, although not very effective.
The income tax legislation dates to the Income Tax Ordinance 1984, and was promulgated under the
military rule. According to the 1984 Ordinance there are seven forms of income on which tax is levied:
salaries, interest on securities, income from house or property, agricultural income, income from
business or profession, capital gains and income from other sources (Income Tax Manual Part-1, 2019). A number of efforts were made to strengthen the revenue mobilization and improve the tax structure.
In 1991 Bangladesh embarked on a major tax reform through the introduction of the VAT system.
Simultaneously there was a significant reduction of import tariffs. Prior to these reforms, trade-based
taxes dominated the tax structure in Bangladesh with customs duties alone accounting for about a third
of tax revenue during the first two decades of the country’s independence.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/how-to-check-ownership-property-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/how-to-check-ownership-property-bangladesh/</link>
      <description> Before buying any property in Bangladesh, it is necessary to check the ownership of the property. In Bangladesh, dispute with property ownership is very common. Documents related to property are easily forged and unreliable. If any person, while buying a property, is not cautious, might face problems, possibly litigation with the ownership of the property at a later stage. However, checking ownership of property in Bangladesh is a laborious job. To check the ownership of a property, a buyer should do the following:

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/recommendations-for-national-board-of-revenue/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/recommendations-for-national-board-of-revenue/</link>
      <description>The major reform of tax administration occurred in the 1990s, in
a democratic regime following military rule in the country. However, there is no study to measure the
effect of democratic environment on the revenue administration and governance. Indirect taxes are still the primary source of government income and contribute the lion’s
share of total tax receipts in Bangladesh. The administration of direct taxes is outdated and based on territorial and geographical administrative
units. As long as withholding taxes at sources has no central database, there is no way for the tax
administration to follow up on additional tax payments and also administer the withholding agencies.
The combined effect of all these deficiencies is the very low tax efficiency and the very low direct tax to
GDP ratio in Bangladesh. Given the context the main recommendations are:

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/income-tax-assessment-procedures/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/income-tax-assessment-procedures/</link>
      <description>In Bangladesh, for a return submitted under normal scheme, assessment is made after giving an opportunity of hearing. For returns submitted under Universal Self Assessment Scheme, the acknowledgement slip is considered to be an assessment order of the Deputy Commissioner of Taxes. Universal Self Assessment may be subject to “process and audit”. Provided that a return of income filed under universal self assessment scheme, shall not be selected for audit where such return shows at least twenty per cent higher income than the income assessed or shown in the return of the immediately preceding assessment year and such return- (a) is accompanied by corroborative evidence in support of income exempted from tax; (b) does not show receipt of gift during the year;(c) does not show any income chargeable to tax at a rate reduced under section 44; or(d) does not show or result any refund.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/winding-up-of-a-company-in-Bangladesh-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/winding-up-of-a-company-in-Bangladesh-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>The winding up or liquidation of a company is the process by which a company’s assets are collected and sold in order to pay its debts. Any monies remaining after all debts, expenses and costs have been paid off are distributed amongst the shareholders of the company. When the winding up has been completed, the company is formally dissolved and it ceases to exist. In Bangladesh, the winding up of a company may be either – (1) Voluntary; or (2) By the court; or (3) Subject to the supervision of the court. Voluntary winding up is usually undertaken by solvent companies, except in the case of creditor’s voluntary winding up. Now we have described the process of voluntary winding up by passing a special resolution.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/avoidance-of-double-taxation-agreement/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/avoidance-of-double-taxation-agreement/</link>
      <description>Double Taxation is created when the same income is taxed in two different countres during international trade. Avoidance of Double Taxation Agreements is an agreement concluded between Bangladesh and another jurisdiction (a treaty partner) which serves to relieve double taxation of income that is earned in one jurisdiction by a resident of the other jurisdiction. It spells out the taxing rights between Bangladesh and her treaty partner on the different types of income arising from cross-border economic activities between the two jurisdictions. It also provides for reduction or exemption of tax on certain types of income.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/copyright-registration-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/copyright-registration-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>Copyright is the exclusive right given to the creator of a creative work to reproduce the work, usually for a limited time. The creative work may be in a literary, artistic, educational, or musical form. Copyright is intended to protect the original expression of an idea in the form of a creative work, but not the idea itself. Under copyright law, a work is considered original if the author created it from independent thinking void of duplication. This type of work is known as Original Work of Authorship (OWA). Anyone with an original work of authorship automatically has the copyright to that work, preventing anyone else from using or replicating it. The copyright can be registered voluntarily by the original owner if he or she would like to get an upper hand in the legal system if the need arises. In Bangladesh, Copyright Office is responsible maintaining the register of copyrighted works. Any application for registration, transfer, abandonment, modification of register should be made to the Registrar.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/foriegn-investment-in-bangladesh-is-protected-by-law/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/foriegn-investment-in-bangladesh-is-protected-by-law/</link>
      <description>Foreign Capital means capital invested in Banladesh in any industrial undertaking by a citizen of any foreign country or by a company incorporated outside Bangladesh, in the form of foreign exchange, imported machinery and equipment and Foreign Private Investment means investment of foreign capital by a person who is not a citizen of Bangladesh or by a company incorporated outside Bangladesh, but does not include investment by a foreign Government or an agency of foreign Government. Foreign investment in Bangladesh is protected by the “Foreign Private Investment Promotion and Protection Act” and also supported by:

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/patent-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/patent-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>An application for a patent may be made by any Bangladeshi or any foreigner, and by alone or jointly with any other person. The application must be made to the Department of Patents, Designs and Trade Marks (DPDT) in the prescribed form. The application must contain a declaration that the applicant is in possession of an invention, whereof he, or in the case of a joint application one at least of the applicants, claims to be the true and first inventor or the legal representative or assign of such inventor and for which he desires to obtain a patent, and must be accompanied by complete specification.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/company-registration-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/company-registration-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>When considering the registration of a new company or relocation of your existing company to Bangladesh, note that most Bangladeshi companies are registered as private limited liability companies (commonly known as private limited companies). A private limited company in Bangladesh is a separate legal entity and shareholders are not liable for the company’s debts beyond the amount of share capital they have contributed. According to the Companies Act 1994, any person (foreign or local) above the age of 18 can register a company in Bangladesh.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/csr-activities-of-banks-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/csr-activities-of-banks-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description> Historically, the banking sector of Bangladesh has been amply participating in various social activities especially, in the areas of education, health, sports, benevolent activities like donations to different charitable organizations, to poor people and religious institutions, city beautification and patronizing art &amp;amp; culture, etc. Bangladesh Bank issued a comprehensive circular titled ‘Mainstreaming  Corporate  Social  Responsibility  (CSR)  in banks  and financial institutions in Bangladesh’. In that circular, CSR was defined as (i) considering the   economic,   social   and   environmental   consequences   of   a   business,   (ii) mitigating the negative impacts and bolstering the benign effects, (iii) initiating action programs and community investments to trim down social exclusion and inequality  as well  as to address  the core sustainable  development  challenges (fulfilling  the  requirements  of  the  current  generation  without  cramping  the capacity of future generations is a generally agreed meaning of ‘sustainable development’).

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/video-tutorial-on-individual-income-tax-return-submission/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/video-tutorial-on-individual-income-tax-return-submission/</link>
      <description>In Bangladesh, filing returns manually is a long process which involves filling up many pages of tax return forms. The process is very difficult and time consuming. There is potential risk of error because of this manual processing of returns. To ensure the public benefit regarding online return submission, National Board of Revenue (NBR), Bangladesh took initiatives of online return submission. The system is simple, smart and easy to use and also help to taxpayers to prepare an accurate tax return without missing any tax benefit. To follow the video tutorial, click on the Read More.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/trademark-registration-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/trademark-registration-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>Trademark registration in Bangladesh is performed through the Department of Patents, Designs and Trademarks (DPDT). Any person claiming to be the proprietor of a trademark already in use or proposed to be used in Bangladesh may apply in writing for registration of a Trademark in the prescribed manner. An applicant has to file application for the registration of a trademark to the Trademark Registry Wing of the DPDT. Service Marks can also be registered in Bangladesh. Applicants can apply for registration of service marks in Bangladesh. The International Nice Classification of Services is applicable for this purpose

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</link>
      <description>Income tax, Company law and Business service provider in Bangladesh</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/what-is-arbitration/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/what-is-arbitration/</link>
      <description> The essence of arbitration is that it is an agreement between two or more parties to try to resolve a dispute outside of the court system. The parties agree upon a third party as an arbitrator who will act as a judge and jury. After giving the parties the opportunity to present their side of the story and to present any relevant documents or other evidence, the arbitrator will act as King Solomon to decide who wins and who loses. 
There are usually no set rules as to how arbitration is conducted. It is typically left to the agreement of the parties. To facilitate the process, though, the parties will oftentimes agree to use the rules of an established organization like the American Arbitration Association. 
There can be binding and non-binding arbitration. A “binding” arbitration generally means that the winning party can take an arbitration award to a court of law and enforce it if the losing party does not comply with the terms of the decision. 
“Non-binding” arbitration refers to a situation where the parties agree to use arbitration as a forum to try to resolve their differences, but neither party is bound to comply with any decision by the arbitrator.

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/about/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/about/</link>
      <description>Income tax, Company law and Business service provider in Bangladesh</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 03:01:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!--<guid value="9dfc70fc-9d2d-42bf-93aa-e46ffcae243a" />-->
<!--Created using XmlSitemapGenerator.org - Free HTML, RSS and XML sitemap generator-->