<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Created using XmlSitemapGenerator.org - Free HTML, RSS and XML sitemap generator-->
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
    <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz</link>
    <description />
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</link>
      <description>Income tax, Company law and Business service provider in Bangladesh</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/feed.xml</guid>
      <title>feed.xml</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/feed.xml</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/working-with-us-following-free-benefits-are-also-available/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/working-with-us-following-free-benefits-are-also-available/</link>
      <description>Working with us following free benefits are also available at no cost to help make life a little bit easier. Personalised e-mail : 01 of our customized e-mail id e.g. yourname@hassanandassociates.biz

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/working-with-us-what-you-will-get/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/working-with-us-what-you-will-get/</link>
      <description>With our 28 years of experience, we take care almost every possible steps to solve problems on case to case basis promptly. It is appreciated everywhere that there is no failure case in our record history. Each of your issue is a partnership. We start with a conversation about your subject matter, then develop a plan with you.  Working with us following benefits are avialable at your end :

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/income-tax-services-of-hassan-and-associates/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/income-tax-services-of-hassan-and-associates/</link>
      <description>Effective tax preparation and planning can help you to minimize your future tax liability. We can help you proactively manage both your personal and business tax issues, including how upcoming business opportunities impact your tax status and vice versa. Not all tax planning opportunities are readily apparent. By having us on your team, you are more likely to benefit from those opportunities as we are constantly identify new ways to reduce your tax liabilities
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/other-business-services-provided-by-the-hassan-and-associates/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/other-business-services-provided-by-the-hassan-and-associates/</link>
      <description>As a true business partner, we stand ready to engage in business consulting projects to help you make the right decisions as we have the necessary business acumen and analytical capabilities. We also to help you get the other types of Govt. registrations, permits, licenses etc. for your business business requirement including financial statements. We tailor each process to the unique needs of your business.
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/company-law-services-of-hassan-and-associates/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/company-law-services-of-hassan-and-associates/</link>
      <description>The business entity - public limited company, private limited company, joint venture company, sole proprietorship, partnership etc. - that you select for your business has enormous financial and tax implications. it is important that you make right decision. we can explain each choice and its implications. As your business grows and changes, the type of business entity you choose may need change and update also.
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/tutorial-on-individual-income-tax-return-submission/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/tutorial-on-individual-income-tax-return-submission/</link>
      <description>
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/legal-system-of-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/legal-system-of-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>Bangladesh is a common law based jurisdiction. Many of the basic laws of Bangladesh such as penal code, civil and criminal procedural codes, contract law and company law are influenced by English common laws. However family laws such as laws relating to marriage, dissolution of marriage and inheritance are based on religious scripts, and therefore differ between religious communities. The Bangladeshi legal system is based on a written constitution and the laws often take statutory forms which are enacted by the legislature and interpreted by the higher courts. Ordinarily executive authorities and statutory corporations cannot make any law, but can make by-laws to the extent authorized by the legislature. Such subordinate legislation is known as rules or regulations and is also enforceable by the court. Yet being a common law system, the statutes are short, and set out basic rights and responsibilities but are elaborated by the courts in their application and interpretation of those. In addition, certain customs and practices established over a period are also to some extent recognized as acceptable and are enforced by the courts.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/income-tax-assessment-procedures/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/income-tax-assessment-procedures/</link>
      <description>For a return submitted under normal scheme, assessment is made after giving an opportunity of hearing.
For  returns  submitted  under  Universal  Self  Assessment  Scheme, the  acknowledgement  slip  is considered to be an assessment order of the Deputy Commissioner of Taxes. Universal Self Assessment may be subject to “process and audit”.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/what-is-arbitration/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/what-is-arbitration/</link>
      <description> The essence of arbitration is that it is an agreement between two or more parties to try to resolve a dispute outside of the court system. The parties agree upon a third party as an arbitrator who will act as a judge and jury. After giving the parties the opportunity to present their side of the story and to present any relevant documents or other evidence, the arbitrator will act as King Solomon to decide who wins and who loses. 
There are usually no set rules as to how arbitration is conducted. It is typically left to the agreement of the parties. To facilitate the process, though, the parties will oftentimes agree to use the rules of an established organization like the American Arbitration Association. 
There can be binding and non-binding arbitration. A “binding” arbitration generally means that the winning party can take an arbitration award to a court of law and enforce it if the losing party does not comply with the terms of the decision. 
“Non-binding” arbitration refers to a situation where the parties agree to use arbitration as a forum to try to resolve their differences, but neither party is bound to comply with any decision by the arbitrator.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/avoidance-of-double-taxation-agreement/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/avoidance-of-double-taxation-agreement/</link>
      <description>Double Taxation is created when the same income is taxed in two different countres during international trade. Avoidance of Double Taxation Agreements is an agreement concluded between Bangladesh and another jurisdiction (a treaty partner) which serves to relieve double taxation of income that is earned in one jurisdiction by a resident of the other jurisdiction. It spells out the taxing rights between Bangladesh and her treaty partner on the different types of income arising from cross-border economic activities between the two jurisdictions. It also provides for reduction or exemption of tax on certain types of income.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/copyright-registration-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/copyright-registration-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>In Bangladesh, Copyright Office is responsible maintaining the register of copyrighted works. Any application for registration, transfer, abandonment, modification of register should be made to the Registrar.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/how-to-check-ownership-property-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/how-to-check-ownership-property-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>Before buying any property in Bangladesh, it is necessary to check the ownership of the property. In Bangladesh, dispute with property ownership is very common. Documents related to property are easily forged and unreliable. If any person, while buying a property, is not cautious, might face problems, possibly litigation with the ownership of the property at a later stage. However, checking ownership of property in Bangladesh is a laborious job. To check the ownership of a property, a buyer should do the following:

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/csr-activities-of-banks-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/csr-activities-of-banks-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description> Historically, the banking sector of Bangladesh has been amply participating in various social activities especially, in the areas of education, health, sports, benevolent activities like donations to different charitable organizations, to poor people  and  religious  institutions,  city  beautification  and  patronizing  art  &amp;amp; culture, etc.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/company-registration-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/company-registration-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>When considering the registration of a new company or relocation of your existing company to Bangladesh, note that most Bangladeshi companies are registered as private limited liability companies (commonly known as private limited companies). A private limited company in Bangladesh is a separate legal entity and shareholders are not liable for the company’s debts beyond the amount of share capital they have contributed. According to the Companies Act 1994, any person (foreign or local) above the age of 18 can register a company in Bangladesh.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/foriegn-investment-in-bangladesh-is-protected-by-law/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/foriegn-investment-in-bangladesh-is-protected-by-law/</link>
      <description>Foreign Capital means capital invested in Banladesh in any industrial undertaking by a citizen of any foreign country or by a company incorporated outside Bangladesh, in the form of foreign exchange, imported machinery and equipment and Foreign Private Investment means investment of foreign capital by a person who is not a citizen of Bangladesh or by a company incorporated outside Bangladesh, but does not include investment by a foreign Government or an agency of foreign Government. Foreign investment in Bangladesh is protected by the “Foreign Private Investment Promotion and Protection Act” and also supported by:

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/patent-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/patent-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>An application for a patent may be made by any Bangladeshi or any foreigner, and by alone or jointly with any other person. The application must be made to the Department of Patents, Designs and Trade Marks (DPDT) in the prescribed form. The application must contain a declaration that the applicant is in possession of an invention, whereof he, or in the case of a joint application one at least of the applicants, claims to be the true and first inventor or the legal representative or assign of such inventor and for which he desires to obtain a patent, and must be accompanied by complete specification.

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/trademark-registration-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/trademark-registration-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>Trademark registration in Bangladesh is performed through the Department of Patents, Designs and Trademarks (DPDT). Any person claiming to be the proprietor of a trademark already in use or proposed to be used in Bangladesh may apply in writing for registration of a Trademark in the prescribed manner. An applicant has to file application for the registration of a trademark to the Trademark Registry Wing of the DPDT. Service Marks can also be registered in Bangladesh. Applicants can apply for registration of service marks in Bangladesh. The International Nice Classification of Services is applicable for this purpose

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/</link>
      <description>Income tax, Company law and Business service provider in Bangladesh</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/about/</guid>
      <title>Hassan and Associates</title>
      <link>https://diary.hassanandassociates.biz/about/</link>
      <description>Income tax, Company law and Business service provider in Bangladesh</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 07:33:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!--<guid value="519d41e8-5d2d-4643-b59a-443f01f6afe8" />-->
<!--Created using XmlSitemapGenerator.org - Free HTML, RSS and XML sitemap generator-->