<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.hassanandassociates.ml/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.hassanandassociates.ml/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-30T13:46:13+06:00</updated><id>https://blog.hassanandassociates.ml/</id><title type="html">Hassan and Associates</title><subtitle>Income tax, Company law and Business services in Bangladesh</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Working with us what you will get ?</title><link href="https://blog.hassanandassociates.ml/working-with-us-what-you-will-get/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working with us what you will get ?" /><published>2017-06-02T00:00:00+06:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T00:00:00+06:00</updated><id>https://blog.hassanandassociates.ml/working-with-us-what-you-will-get</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.hassanandassociates.ml/working-with-us-what-you-will-get/">&lt;p&gt;With our 28 years of experience, we take care almost every possible steps to solve problems on case to case basis promptly. It is appreciated everywhere that there is no failure case in our record history. Each of your issue is a partnership. We start with a conversation about your subject matter, then develop a plan with you. &lt;br /&gt; Working with us following benefits are avialable at your end :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Free Advice : We provide free advice on request.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hassele-Free : We provide quick and accurate assessement and hassle-free services.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Storage Facility : You may store your service related documents online securely and access them anytime from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Data Encryption : We maintain bank-level data encryption and protection.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Documentation Support : We provide reliable online and manual documetaion support.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download : Unlimited data revisions, PDF print and downloads.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Professional Team : We have a good professional team to achieve our professional goal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More Features : To know about other avialable features, Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfpEu18GwtXckk8qpcwxNPhRjHXEoeSP27mc_H-ycduDNzKIA/viewform&quot;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">With our 28 years of experience, we take care almost every possible steps to solve problems on case to case basis promptly. It is appreciated everywhere that there is no failure case in our record history. Each of your issue is a partnership. We start with a conversation about your subject matter, then develop a plan with you. Working with us following benefits are avialable at your end :</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Choose Us ?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/why-choose-us/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Choose Us ?" /><published>2017-06-01T00:00:00+06:00</published><updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/why-choose-us</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/why-choose-us/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a firm that will focus on your individual needs and always treat you like a client who matters, look no further. Having 28 years experience our firm is enough to offer a full range of professional and customized services to give you the individual attention that you deserve. We will throughly and conscientiously study your personal situation and tailor our advice to your specific needs. Although we’re a team  for providing our services in Dhaka, Bangladesh but we serve clients across the country and all over the world. We take pride in our commitment to the highest standards of integrity and honesty. We’ll never make false assurances or promises. Your trust is far too important to us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you’re looking for a firm that will focus on your individual needs and always treat you like a client who matters, look no further. Having 28 years experience our firm is enough to offer a full range of professional and customized services to give you the individual attention that you deserve. We will throughly and conscientiously study your personal situation and tailor our advice to your specific needs. Although we’re a team for providing our services in Dhaka, Bangladesh but we serve clients across the country and all over the world. We take pride in our commitment to the highest standards of integrity and honesty. We’ll never make false assurances or promises. Your trust is far too important to us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basis of Consideration ?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basis-of-consideration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basis of Consideration ?" /><published>2017-05-29T00:00:00+06:00</published><updated>2017-05-29T00:00:00+06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basis-of-consideration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basis-of-consideration/">&lt;p&gt;The best way to empower you is to seek help from a professional income tax, company law and other business services provider firm. While choosing the right one, you must verify a few questions. The important things to be considered are for how long the service peovider is in this field, what is the educational qualification of the members of the firm, whether he is a memeber in the local Taxes Bar Association or not. Once you get satisfied answers to these questions, it is safe to go ahead in order to get professional and customized services&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The best way to empower you is to seek help from a professional income tax, company law and other business services provider firm. While choosing the right one, you must verify a few questions. The important things to be considered are for how long the service peovider is in this field, what is the educational qualification of the members of the firm, whether he is a memeber in the local Taxes Bar Association or not. Once you get satisfied answers to these questions, it is safe to go ahead in order to get professional and customized services</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Do You Really Need a Professional Service ?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/do-you-really-need-a-professional-service/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do You Really Need a Professional Service ?" /><published>2017-05-22T00:00:00+06:00</published><updated>2017-05-22T00:00:00+06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/do-you-really-need-a-professional-service</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/do-you-really-need-a-professional-service/">&lt;p&gt;Like any other country, in Bangladesh specially the taxation policies are also quite hectic and complicated that people fail to understand that. Mostly for an outsider the taxation rules tough to understand. One can find a huge versatility in the taxation. A slight error in the preparation of income tax returns can further complicate the problem and make you experience great hassles. Whether you are a business owner or an individual, tax is something that you will have to file within specified deadlines and no one can avoid. Being an individual or a limited company to handle all this while handle the business is quite a headache and this is where a professinal services are being hired for customized tax and other business related planning. So, this customized planning is very important for a safe future. You might earn a lot, but if can’t save a money in this proper way, hard consequences awaiting you in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Like any other country, in Bangladesh specially the taxation policies are also quite hectic and complicated that people fail to understand that. Mostly for an outsider the taxation rules tough to understand. One can find a huge versatility in the taxation. A slight error in the preparation of income tax returns can further complicate the problem and make you experience great hassles. Whether you are a business owner or an individual, tax is something that you will have to file within specified deadlines and no one can avoid. Being an individual or a limited company to handle all this while handle the business is quite a headache and this is where a professinal services are being hired for customized tax and other business related planning. So, this customized planning is very important for a safe future. You might earn a lot, but if can’t save a money in this proper way, hard consequences awaiting you in the near future.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Contact us !</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Contact-us/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contact us !" /><published>2017-03-17T00:00:00+06:00</published><updated>2017-03-17T00:00:00+06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Contact-us</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Contact-us/">&lt;p&gt;We are providing services for individual and company income tax, company registration, annual return update, company law matter including all other related business services. We are located in Dhaka, Bangladesh but we serve clients across the country and all over the world. Our other Business services includes obtaining Trade License, Value Added Tax Registration certificate, Membership of Chamber of Commerce, Import-Export-Indenting License, Permits, Trademark-Copyright-Patent registration, project profile preparation as well as obtaining approval from the concern Authority etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/logos/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;_config.yml&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get more information about our services, Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfpEu18GwtXckk8qpcwxNPhRjHXEoeSP27mc_H-ycduDNzKIA/viewform&quot;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are providing services for individual and company income tax, company registration, annual return update, company law matter including all other related business services. We are located in Dhaka, Bangladesh but we serve clients across the country and all over the world. Our other Business services includes obtaining Trade License, Value Added Tax Registration certificate, Membership of Chamber of Commerce, Import-Export-Indenting License, Permits, Trademark-Copyright-Patent registration, project profile preparation as well as obtaining approval from the concern Authority etc</summary></entry></feed>